<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Miguel Nogueira</title>
    <link>https://www.miguelnogueira.com/</link>
    <description>Miguel Nogueira</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
    <atom:link href="https://www.miguelnogueira.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>https://www.miguelnogueira.com/posts/hello_world/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.miguelnogueira.com/posts/hello_world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Old webpage was getting a bit long in the tooth so decided to find a new theme, customize it a bit and refresh the site. It may not be the final one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time with blog functionality, so that I can post some things I&amp;rsquo;ve been musing about. Key word is &amp;ldquo;can&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip; let&amp;rsquo;s see if I will&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.miguelnogueira.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.miguelnogueira.com/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a Computer Science Engineer MSc majored in Software Engineering and with a minor in Enterprise Information Systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For years I worked as an EAI and Order Management Consultant for &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.novabase.pt&#34;&gt;Novabase&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.celfocus.com&#34;&gt;Celfocus&lt;/a&gt; in the Telco market mainly for Vodafone OpCos with roles spanning from Development, Functional and Technical Analysis, Architecture, Team Leading and Production Acceptance mostly in the BSS (Business Support Systems) stack but with some dips into OSS (Operational Support Systems).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of 2018 I embraced a new career path and started working as a Backend Engineer for a startup studio, which was relatively shortlived since 11 months later I left due to not agreeing to how it was being managed. There I was the backend engineer of a recruitment product named &lt;a href=&#34;https://atomichire.com&#34;&gt;Atomichire&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, and since the very end of September 2019, I work as a Solution Designer/Architect at &lt;a href=&#34;https://worten.pt&#34;&gt;Worten&lt;/a&gt; - the largest portuguese electronics retailer - with a focus on Platform (EventHub, API Gateway, Auth, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find my up-to-date resumé on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/madril/&#34;&gt;Linkedin&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a more personal note I can be identified as a Petrolhead, a Gamer and a F.C. Porto supporter.
For my computing needs I pend towards Apple hardware and software both on the go and for working purposes.
To hear some of my personal thoughts regarding these and other topics you can probably still find me on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.twitter.com/Madril&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;. Haven&amp;rsquo;t been in Facebook for over three years now, so not even worth linking to it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
